That's the Mist-Shrouded Cape.
あれが雲隠れ岬
本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
どうする
What will you do?
やめるなら 今のうちだよ
This is your last chance to back out.
O maiden!
otome yo
Flare up in the dawning sun!
akatsuki ni moeagare
I want to tear off the guise of the ignorant
muchi de kayowaku mamorareru dake no
Frail protected princess and live
hime nugisutete watashi wa ikitai
To conquer the color of the burning dawn
mukashi yori sukoshi dake suki ni nareta
That I've recently started enjoying
akatsuki no sora no iro nabikase
With strength and commanding presence
rinzen to tsuyoku
I strive to be someone I'm proud of
kedakaku sora wo miagete
And looking up idealistically to the sky
hokoreru jibun ni narou
To protect, to love, to stand my ground
mamori aishi tsuranuku
I won't allow myself to lose anything again
keshite ubawasenai
Like a noble flower
kedakai hana no you ni
With single-minded passion
hitamuki na jounetsu de
Even if faced with a cruel fate
zankoku na sadame sae
I will push through
kirihiraite miseru kara
Episode 19:      The Senjuso Test
A life-threatening job?
命がけの仕事
今のお前は何の役にも立たないお荷物だ
Right now, you're useless baggage.
それでも私らと一緒にクムジと戦うってんなら
But if you insist on fighting Kum-ji with us,
you must demonstrate your resolve.
それ相応の覚悟を見せてもらうよ
覚悟
My resolve...
分かった 何をすればいいの
I understand. What do I have to do?
千樹草を取ってきてもらおうか
Pick me some senjuso.
Captain, isn't that-
船長 それは...
口を挟むんじゃないよ
Don't interrupt me.
お前には無理だろ
You could never do it.
千樹草って
What's senjuso?
雲隠れ岬にしか生えない貴重な薬草でね
It's a valuable medicinal herb that grows only on the Mist-Shrouded Cape...
A cure-all that speeds up healing
of illnesses and wounds.
病や傷の治りを激的に早める万能薬さ
A cure-all?
万能薬
千樹草があれば今負傷している仲間も早く回復する
With the senjuso, my injured
men will recover quickly.
これからの戦いに大いに必要なものだ
In our upcoming battle,
we will have great need for it.
丁度いつも取りに行っている奴が負傷しててね
The man I usually send to pick it
is currently injured.
そいつの代わりをしてくれなら お前を認めてやるよ
If you'll do it in his place, I'll accept you.
分かった
Fine.
Oh, I forgot to mention...
言い忘れてたけど
千樹草は断崖絶壁の中腹に生えている
The senjuso grows in the middle of a sheer cliff.
誰の手も借りずに一人で行くんだよ
You'll go alone, without anyone's help.
Huh?
初めからそのつもり
That was already my intention.
Yona, this is crazy!
ヨナ 無茶だよ
ユン お願い
Yun... Please.
これは私の 仕事だから
This is my job.
いい心掛けだ
Good attitude.
ジェハ 案内しておやり
Jae-ha, show her the way.
はい はい
All right, all right.
じゃあ ちょっと行ってくる
Well, I'm off.
すぐ戻るね
I'll be back soon.
あそこに小さな足場があるだろう
You see that narrow path?
そこから降りていくと
ちょうど君が入れるくらいの空洞がある
It will take you to a cave
just large enough for you to fit in.
そこにある千樹草を摘んでくる
Pick the senjuso there.
それだけだ
That's all.
簡単だろう
Easy, right?
簡単
"Easy"? Even I know that was mean.
我ながら意地悪だな
この状況に足が竦まない人間はいない
This situation would paralyze anyone with fear.
試しとはいえ ギガン船長も酷なことを
Captain Gi-gan's tests are ruthless.
Okay!
よし
大丈夫
It's all right.
ギガン船長は体の小さな私に見合う仕事をくれたのよ
Captain Gi-gan gave me this job
after seeing how small I am.
My legs won't move.
足が 動かない
嫌だ ここに居たくない
I don't want to be here!
I'm afraid! I'm afraid!
Help me!
助けて
I don't want to die!
死にたくない
Calm down.
落ち着いて
The wind isn't that strong.
大して風じゃない
先代が言っていた
My predecessor told me that
緋龍王とは四龍にとっては血に刻まれた絶対なる君主
absolute devotion to King Hiryuu was etched into the blood of the four dragons.
I wondered what sort of man would come.
どんな男が来るのかと思っていた
きっと強大な力で四龍を支配する
偉ぶった野郎なんだろうと
I imagined a conceited man, who would use force to command the dragons.
しかし
However, the one standing here is a weak girl,
without any special strength.
ここにいるのは特別な力など何も持たない
まぎれもないか弱い少女
あの時 四龍を統べる者だと 僕の血が認めた
At that moment, my blood recognized her as the one to rule the four dragons.
だが
But is this weak girl trembling before me that person?
目の前のこんなにも弱い震えている少女が
その人だというのか
Is she really the four dragons' master?
本当に 彼女が四龍の主なのか
ヨナちゃん 無理することはない
Yona, you don't need to force yourself.
怖ければ 戻ればいい
If you're afraid, come back.
船長の与えた仕事は無理だ
The job the captain gave you is impossible.
よって 君は僕らとともにクムジと戦うことはできないけれど
It would mean you can't fight
against Kum-ji with us,
だれもそんなこと強制していないのだから
but no one is forcing you to do this.
君が自ら危険に飛び込む必要はない
You don't need to put yourself in danger!
そうだ 戻れ
That's right. Come back.
君は女の子なんだから
You're only a girl.
戻れ
Come back.
Yona!
ヨナ
I won't go back.
戻れ...ない
大丈夫
It's okay.
何が大丈夫だ
It is not okay!
こんな 簡単な仕事
I have to do this simple job.
It isn't simple!
何が簡単だ
If I don't, I won't be able to face
Captain Gi-gan or Hak and the others.
こなせなきゃ ギガン船長は勿論
ハク達にも 合わせる顔ないもの
Ao, thank you.
アオ ありがとう
頑張る
I'll do my best.
震えるが 止まった訳でも
涙が止まった訳でもないのに
How can you keep moving forward,
when you're still trembling and crying?
どうして進める
君のような力のない女の子が
You're only a powerless girl!
ヨナちゃん
Yona?
よかった 薬が目的で
I'm glad I'm here to get the medicine.
どうして
Why?
例えば
Suppose Hak, Yun, Ki-ja, or Sin-ha were gravely injured right now.
今 ハクやユン キジャやシンアが大怪我をしてたとして
千樹草があれば治るものであったなら
If the senjuso could heal them,
I'd do anything to acquire it.
私は何があっても取りに行く
例え矢の降る戦場の真ん中に生えていても 取りに行く
Even if it were growing in the middle of a battlefield with arrows raining down,
I would still go to pick it.
When I think of it that way,
I can go anywhere.
そう思えば どこへだって行けるよ
足 震えてるよ
Your legs are shaking.
誰が失うのが怖いかい
Are you afraid of losing someone?
怖い
I am afraid.
I fear that more than anything else.
それが一番怖いの
I fear seeing someone crying
over losing another, too.
誰かを失って泣く人を見るのも
誰かを失いたくないという思いが
Her desire not to lose anyone
moves her shaking legs forward.
震える足を前に進ませるのか
Right now, she acts for the people of Awa who are terrified of Kum-ji.
今は クムジに怯える阿波の人々のため
どこかのバカと同じだ
She reminds me of some idiots I know.
いや 少し力があるだけ バカのがましだね
No, at least an idiot is better off
for having a little strength.
見てらんない
I can't watch this anymore.
Jae-ha...
ジェハ
ついてきてくれるの
You're coming with me?
Huh? Oh...
Well, partway. I'm keeping an eye on you.
まぁ まぁ 途中までね 見張りだよ
Thank you.
ありがとう
Just so you know, I won't help you.
言っとくけど 手は貸さないよ
I know, but having your voice nearby is reassuring.
うん でも あなたの声が近くにあると 安心するの
そこに居てくれるだけで
Just having you near.
I wonder why.
どうしてかな
Why? I'd like to ask you the same question.
どうして
こっちが聞きたいよ
この僕が もっと君の声を 姿を
感じていたいと思うなんて 初めて会った時よりも
Why do I want to hear and see you now, even more than when we first met?
これも四龍の血が僕の体に流れているせいだろう
It must be because of the dragon's blood
flowing through my veins.
きっとそうに違いない
That must be it.
それ以外 何がある
What else could it be?
なんて四龍の血とは 厄介なんだ
The dragon's blood is such a pain in the ass.
さて 僕はここまでだよ
This is as far as I'll go.
この先は狭くて僕は行けない
The path ahead is too narrow for me.
君だけで行くんだ
You'll have to go alone.
ずっと 強くなりたかった
I always wanted to become stronger.
初めは自分を守るため
At first, it was to protect myself.
次は 私のためにすべてを捨ててきたハクを守るため
Next, it was to protect Hak,
who gave up everything for me.
そして 私を生かしてくれた仲間達に報いるため
Now, it's to repay my friends,
who enabled me to live.
Move, legs!
足よ 動け
Little by little, one step at a time.
少しずつでも 一方ずつでも
この恐怖に打ち勝てば
If I can beat this fear, surely I will be that much closer to the strength I desired.
きっと
欲しかった強さに 近づける気がするから
これが千樹草
This is the senjuso?
よかった
Thank goodness.
私にも辿り着けた
I made it here.
どうしました 船長
What is it, Captain?
時化てきたね
The water's getting choppy.
え そうっすか
Huh? It is?
この分じゃ 急がないとあの娘やばいね
That girl will be in trouble if she doesn't hurry.
Thunder Beast?
雷獣
What do you want?
なんたい
案内してくれ
Show me the way.
Yona, are you okay?
ヨナちゃん 大丈夫
Yes.
Yona!
ヨナ
Go back inside!
戻れ
Yona?
ヨナちゃん
ヨナ
Yona!
何てことだ こんな近くにいて助けられないなんて
I don't believe it.
I was so close, but I couldn't save her.
That weak... That weak girl.
あんなに あんなにか弱い少女を
ジェハ
Jae-ha...
ヨナちゃん
Yona!
大丈夫か 今助ける
Are you okay? I'll save you.
No!
ダメ
If you help me now,
then my promise to Captain Gi-gan...
ここで手を借りたら
ギガン船長との約束が
君って子は
You're unbelievable.
ジェハ
Jae-ha?
まったく 凄い子だよ 君は
You know, you're incredible.
この僕をここまでハラハラさせるんだからね
You manage to leave me breathless.
結局 助けられちゃった
I needed your help, after all.
見損なわないでほしいな
Don't get the wrong idea.
僕は本来 女性は真綿でくるむように大事にする主義なんだ
Treating women with the greatest care
is one of my principles.
なにわ笑ってんだい 能天気
What are you laughing about?
この海に飛び込んでまで助けようとしてくれたのね
You were ready to jump into the sea to save me.
ありがとう
Thank you.
Don't tell the captain.
船長には内緒だ
Huh? But...
でも
It's that.
それ
You picked and protected the senjuso yourself.
その千樹草は君が自分の力で手に入れ 守った
だから船長との約束は果たされたんだ
You kept your promise to the captain.
What I did was just a bonus.
僕が今やったことはおまけ
船長に言う必要はない
You don't need to tell the captain about it.
I haven't done anything yet.
まだ 全然果たせてないわ
これを持って 皆の元へ帰らないと
I need to take this back to the others.
ね こんなところに生えてるの 千樹草
So the senjuso grows here?
I told you it was a sheer cliff.
Princess...
言ったろう 絶壁だって
Yeah, but it's too steep!
絶壁すぎでしょ
This is crazy!
無茶だよ
The waves are choppy.
海は荒れてるし
ヨナなんか風に飛ばされちゃうよ
The wind could blow Yona away!
私が降りてお助けする
I'll go rescue her!
Wait!
お待ち
あの娘は私の信頼を得るために
この仕事を引き受けたんだよ
That girl accepted this job to earn my trust.
お前らはその覚悟を踏みにじる気かい
Are you willing to stomp all over her resolve?
しかし何があったら
But if something happened to her...
ヨナは女の子なんだよ
Yona is a girl!
女だって戦わなければならない時があるんだ
Sometimes, women must fight too.
舐めるんじゃないよ
Don't underestimate us.
Hak, are you all right with this?
ハク そなたはよいのか
ハク
Hak!
ヨナ
Yona...
Yona!
もう バカ バカ
Geez, you idiot!
無茶ばっかり
You're always so reckless!
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
Where is the senjuso?
千樹草は
ここに
Here.
So it is.
確かに
じゃ約束通りお前を
Then, as promised, you-
No.
いいえ
Jae-ha helped me.
私 ジェハに助けてもらいました
突然の大波に海に投げ出されそうになって 助けてもらったの
A sudden wave nearly carried me out to sea, and he saved me.
I couldn't do it alone.
私一人の力じゃ なしえなかった
では 諦めるんだね
Then you're giving up?
いいえ
No.
もう一度 一人で取ってくる
I'm going to get it myself this time.
She's great...
海に投げ出された女を見殺しなんてまねしたら
If Jae-ha had let a girl tossed into the sea die,
I would have thrown him into the sea myself.
私がジェハを海に叩き落としていたよ
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
Wow, scary...
That's why I love you,
Captain.
目が真っ赤だね
Your eyes are red.
だいぶ泣いただろう
You must have cried a lot.
塩水が目に入っただけよ
I just got salt water in my eyes!
手は傷だらけ
Your hands are covered in cuts.
足はがくがく
Your legs are shaking.
根性あるじゃないか
You've got guts.
お前見たい奴は 窮地に立たされても決して仲間を裏切らない
Someone like you would never betray her friends,
even in the most desperate of situations.
そういうバカは嫌いじゃないよ
I don't mind idiots like you.
船に乗りな
Climb aboard!
Huh?
君は合格だよ ヨナちゃん
You pass, Yona.
All...
や やった
All right!
よかったね ヨナちゃん
That's great, Yona!
A girl!
You did so well!
頑張った
She's great...
Yona, how old are you?
ヨナちゃん いくつ
ほら 汚い手でそのお方に触れるでない
Such a cute girl
Hey! Don't touch her with your filthy hands!
あの子が絡むと 君はそういう顔がするんだね
So that's the kind of expression
she puts on your face.
あんたこそ 十年くらい老け込んだ顔になってんぞ
Look who's talking.
You look ten years older.
Huh? That's not good!
Mirror
m 285 534 l 284 501 302 481 326 472 335 468 347 469 357 471 370 473 387 484 396 499 395 508 383 512 360 507 346 507 320 519
それはいけない 本当に
Currently 25 Years Old
m 174 679 l 170 621 196 594 538 571 622 584 637 601 638 674 457 685
Really?
Currently 25 Years Old
m 174 679 l 170 621 196 594 538 571 622 584 637 601 638 674 457 685
She was so determined to keep going, I thought I'd lose years off my life.
彼女があまりに必死で引き下がらないから 寿命が縮む思いだったよ
随分入れ込んでんな
You're pretty deeply engaged in this.
僕は女の子にはいつだって入れ込むよ
When it comes to girls,
I'm always deeply engaged.
However, I've never met anyone like her.
でも あんな子は初めてだ
純粋で頑固で そのくせ足元はふらふらで
If you must touch her, at least wash your hands first!
She's pure and stubborn,
but unsteady on her feet.
Who do you think you are?
I'd consider her a huge pain in the ass.
僕にとっては非常に厄介でめんどくさい
I am clean as the purest white.
See?! This happened because you touched her!
I can't understand why anyone
would want to protect her.
護衛する奴の気が知れないね
まぁな
I guess...
よっぽと大切なんだね
She must be really important.
まっ 幼馴染だし
Well, we're old friends.
恋人
Lovers?
まさか
Yeah, right.
大事な 預かりもんだ
She's an important person left in my care.
預かりものね
Left in your care, huh?
What?
なんだよ
なんとなく 君と彼女は近いようでいて
距離があるなと思ってさ
I get the impression you're very close,
but there's some distance between you.
Huh?
Maybe it's because you don't really want her.
それって君が彼女を本気で欲しいと思ってないあらかな
でっかいお世話だ
Mind your own business.
Why would you say that?
なんでてめぇがそんなこと
なんでかなぁ
Why, indeed?
彼女に興味を持ったからかも
Maybe it's because I'm interested in her.
Just kidding.
うそ
今のハクの顔 面白かったよ
That was an interesting face you just made.
ちょっと疲れが取れた
I feel a bit rejuvenated.
彼女を本気で欲しいと思ってないからかな
Maybe it's because you don't really want her.
知るか そんなこと
Whatever...
ずっと ずっと兄妹見たいに側にいて
We've... We've been like siblings forever.
彼奴と姫さんが治める国を守ろうと
I lived every day sworn to protect the kingdom
that he and the princess would rule together.
それだけを誓って 日々を生きてきた
今 なんとか生きようとしている姫さんに
Now, the princess is just trying to survive.
イル陛下からの大事な預かり者である姫さんに
This princess left in my care by King Il...
これ以上 望むとこなど
There's nothing more I could ask of her.
なに泣いてるんっすか
What are you crying about?
なん なんでもないわ
N-Nothing.
痛い痛い痛い
Ow, ow, ow!
なんだこりゃ
What's this?
千樹草取りに行ったときに木の棘がいっぱい刺さって
I pricked myself on a lot of thorns when I went to pick the senjuso.
I heard I could get them out with a needle.
針で取るものだって聞いたから
ぐりぐりと針で抉ってたわけですかい
So you tore up your hands with a needle?
凄く痛いのに取れないと
It really hurt, but I couldn't get anything out!
針は火で炙りましたか
Did you heat the needle with a flame?
Huh? Why would I do that?
なにそれ
大変だ
This is terrible!
傷口が化膿して明日には手が腐って落ちますよ
Your wounds will fester, and tomorrow, your hands will rot off!
Huh?!
刺すわよ
I'll stab you!
In any case, clean your wounds.
とりあえず 傷口を洗ってください
Okay.
ユンの荷物勝手に漁ったら怒られちゃうよ
Yun will get mad at you for
digging through his things.
緊急事態だ 仕方ない
This is an emergency. I have no choice.
あった
Here it is.
Is that honey?
それ蜂蜜
Huh? What are you doing?
なにをするの
これを患部に塗って しばらく置けば
自然に棘は出てきます
If you leave it on the affected area for a while,
the thorns will come out on their own.
本当に
Really?
昔は爺によく針で抉られて
The old man used to stab me
with needles all the time.
When I learned there was an easier way to get them out, I wanted to kill him.
こんな楽な方法があると知った時は殺意芽生えたね
ムンドクらしいわ
That sounds like Mun-deok.
本当に
I can't believe the way your hands look, Princess.
なんて手してんですか お姫様が
Do you think I've gotten stronger?
私 少しは強くなれた？
少しはハクに近づけたかな
Am I closer to you now?
You're very close, but there's
some distance between you.
君と彼女は近いようで距離がある
本気で欲しいと思ってないからかな
Maybe it's because you don't really want her.
うるせぇな たれ目
Shut up, droopy eyes.
You're probably right.
多分 そうなんだろうよ
そういつは今まで 何度も押し殺してきたんだから
Up to now, I've suppressed my desire countless times.
ハク
Hak?
蜂蜜垂れてる
The honey is dripping!
Huh?
U-Um, H-Hak...
あ あの ハ ハク
Ha...
Hak!
ハク
もう...いい
That's... enough.
なにやってんだ 俺は
What am I doing?
姫さんが自由に生きる
The princess can live freely.
Be satisfied with that, you idiot.
それで満足しとけ 馬鹿野郎
I don't need desire making an appearance now.
今更 欲なんて 顔を出してくれるなよ
お前の取ってきた千樹草で
仲間の容態が回復に向かっているそうだ
My men are recovering because of
the senjuso you brought.
みんなお前に感謝してるってよ
Everyone is grateful to you.
I'm glad.
よかった
もう 犠牲を出してたくないからね
I don't want to lose anyone else.
亡くなった人がいるの
Have you lost people?
そりゃあね 海賊なんてやってんだ
Of course. We are pirates.
無傷ってわけにはいかないよ
Injuries are part of our life.
この戦いが終わったら 海賊を解散して
Once this battle is over,
I want to disband my pirate crew,
彼奴らを普通の生活に戻してやりたいんだ
so they can return to living normal lives.
そう...なの
Really?
一人だけ難しい奴がいるがね
There's just one problem.
難しい
A problem?
ジェハだよ
Jae-ha.
彼奴はこの船が家だからね
This ship is his home.
異形の存在故 ここが一番居心地よいのさ
Because he's different,
he feels most comfortable here.
Once the pirates disband,
will Jae-ha be alone?
じゃ 海賊を解散したら ジェハは一人になるの
お前が 連れてってくれるかい
Would you take him with you?
そうしたいけど 私と行くのは嫌だって
I'd like to, but he doesn't want to go with me.
Maybe he's not ready to leave the nest.
彼奴はまだ親離れできないのかね
心外だなぁ船長
That's not true, Captain.
僕は本来 一人が好きなんだよ
I like being alone.
海賊がなくなったって 気ままにやっていくさ
Once the pirates are gone, I'll simply do as I please.
それこそ 異形の龍達とつるんで何になるんだい
What good will joining those other dragons do?
ヨナちゃんと二人旅なら考えるけど
But I'd consider traveling with only Yona.
Oh, but I'm not interested in looking after a child.
でも 子守はしんどいから
もう少し大人の女性になったらね
I'll join you once you're a little older.
Crying tears for the days that won't return
modoranai hibi ni namida koboshite
ジェハは意地悪ね
You're so mean, Jae-ha!
ハクみたい
You're just like Hak!
Oh? Interesting.
Don't lump me
with this guy
それは面白い
Don't lump me
with this guy
How unusual.
珍しいね
You look up to the sky, and it's burning bright red
miageta sora ga akaku akaku moeru
Usually, you're smooth as silk with women.
女と見れば砂吐くようなセリフしか言わないのに
Silk...?
気になってんのかい あの娘
Are you interested in her?
Now that you know your own strength and weakness
jibun no tsuyosa yowasa kizuketa no nara ima
You must be joking.
御冗談を
Sin-ha? What's wrong?
シンア どうしたの
Boats are gathering in the harbor.
船が 港に 集まって来ている
You should have no fear and go where your heart takes you
kimi yo osoreruna kokoro omomuku mama
何隻だい
How many?
Cleaving through the wind, your path is lit
kaze wo kirisusumu sono tabiji wo
Seven.
七隻
Seven ships?
People with weapons are riding in the ships.
武器を持った人が乗ってる
By the dawn
akatsuki ga terasu
(Gather, fierce arm)
(tsudoe takeki kaina)
Is Kum-ji trying to intimidate us?
クムジめ 私らを威嚇してるつもりかい
(All-seeing eyes)
(senri no hitomi)
Feet that dash through the sky
sora wo kakeyuku ashi
Interesting.
面白いじゃないか
(Shield of eternity)
(kuon no tate)
Fulfill the ancient vows
inishie no chikai ima hatashite
滔々動き出したみたいだね
He's finally making his move.
What's going on?
一体 なにが
ついに戦いが始まったのさ
The battle is finally starting.
O night, break into dawn
yoru yo akete yuke
Gather the men.
小僧共 集めな
クムジは徐々に戦力を増やしつつある
Kum-ji is strengthening his forces.
それは恐らくクムジにとって一番大事な取引が近くに控えているから
It's probably because his most
important deal is coming up.
With the Kai Empire.
戒帝国との間でね
戒帝国
The Kai Empire?
と言っても 阿波近くの一部の連中
Just with a group near Awa, actually.
クムジのお得意様と言った所さ
They're one of Kum-ji's regular trading partners.
What makes the deal so important?
一番大事な取引というのは
人身売買さ
It's human trafficking.
Next Time
It's okay.
大丈夫だよ
俺が行くからには 絶対にヨナは死なせない
Since I'm going, I can guarantee Yona won't die.
次回 暁のヨナ 第二十話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 20:
Episode 20:      Chain of Courage
勇気の連鎖
Chain of Courage.